<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Travis Spear</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Travis Spear</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Caret for Quick Model Comparison in R</title>
      <link>/post/caret-for-quick-model-comparison-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/caret-for-quick-model-comparison-in-r/</guid>
      <description>R has hundreds, if not thousands, of packages providing access to machine learning algorithms. With the variety of naming conventions, function requirements, and output structures provided throughout these packages comparing results can become a nuisance. To streamline the process of testing and comparing models from many R packages, the caret package provides an interface to over 500 popular algorithms aggregated from across the R community.
To demonstrate the ease of testing and comparing multiple model types, I will revisit the Titanic dataset to predict passenger survival using 5 common algorithm types and then create an ensemble model with the outputs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Literature Bias in Alzheimer&#39;s Disease Clinical Trials</title>
      <link>/post/aan2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/aan2019/</guid>
      <description>In 2019 I had the opportunity to share some of my research at the American Academy of Neurologists in Philadelphia. Here I’ll provide my poster as well as a few reasons for my excitement about the topic of literature bias in Alzheimer’s Disease.
What This Research Contributes:The largest review of Alzheimer’s literature focusing on biasExpands on previous Funding bias research in Alzheimer’s DiseaseProvides non-anecdotal exploration into Publishing Journal as a source of biasIntroduces Author Affiliations as a potential biasing factorBackgroundIn clinical research, the Randomized Controlled Trial (RCT) is considered the gold standard due to it’s ability to mitigate the amount of bias introduced by investigators and patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parallel Plots for Exploratory Analysis of Clinical Trial Literature Reviews</title>
      <link>/post/parallel-plots/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/parallel-plots/</guid>
      <description>In the pursuit of more data-centric medical decisions large scale literature reviews are increasingly necessary, however, results of these literature reviews are often hard to depict outside of numeric tables. I’ll be exploring the use of parallel plots as a complementary reporting tool for literature reviews through their ability to display hundreds of clinical trials on a single graph.
This idea was inspired by an excellent set of plots from 538.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/travisspear_cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/travisspear_cv/</guid>
      <description>SummaryAmbitious data professional with experience handling data from a variety of disciplines across an organization. Expertise enhancing company data practices through automation, predictive analytics, andartificial intelligence using modern programming languages. Proven ability to communicate the impact of analytical findings to a wide range of audiences through innovative data visualizations.
Career InterestsNatural Language ProcessingMedical/Healthcare ApplicationsData Stream/IOT AnalyticsBusiness AnalyticsCore SkillsPrimary Languages : R, Python, SQL</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>